Who was that lady I saw you outwit last night? That was
no lady … That was ‘Mum’ Wilberforce, …
The Ladykillers is a comedy, crime film directed by Alexander Mackendrick.
Five oddball criminals planning a bank robbery rent rooms on a cul-de-sac from an
octogenarian widow under the pretext that they are classical musicians.
Professor Marcus, played by Alec Guinness.
Claude, alias 'Major Courtney', played by Cecil Parker.
Louis, alias 'Mr. Harvey', played by Herbert Lom.
Harry, alias 'Mr. Robinson', played by Peter Sellers.
'One-Round', alias 'Mr. Lawson', played by Danny Green.
Mrs. Wilberforce, played by Katie Johnson.
The Ladykillers is a 1955 British black comedy crime film
directed by Alexander Mackendrick for Ealing Studios.
It stars Alec Guinness, Cecil Parker, Herbert Lom, Peter Sellers, Danny
Green, Jack Warner, and Katie Johnson as the old lady, Mrs.
Wilberforce.
William Rose wrote the screenplay, for which he was nominated for an Academy Award for Best
Original Screenplay and won the BAFTA Award for Best British Screenplay.
He claimed to have dreamt the entire film and merely had
to remember the details when he awoke.
The film explores themes of widow, dark comedy, parrot, gang of thieves, money.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.